Contact

vivinino84@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/viviananiño-24671b15 (LinkedIn) be.net/vivinino (Personal) vimeo.com/user3676858 (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Art Direction
Graphic Design
Project Management

Languages

English advanced level (Native or Bilingual)

Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Catalán basic level

Italian basic level

Certifications

Master Degree in Digital Compositing and Motion Graphics

Viviana Niño

VFX Producer/Post Production & Studio Manager at SraX productions

Barcelona

Summary

Passionate for creating and developing visual content closely with great artists and teams.

My latest roles have been in-house VFX Production Coordinator, Postproduction for short films, and 3D Animated content.

My experience includes operating an accredited VFX & Film college, producing/coordinating and managing resources for diversified projects.

I've specialized in combining action live with VFX & Animated content during all stages of production, as well as On set shooting.

With an education in Graphic design, Motion graphics, Compositing, Art Direction & Communications Strategie. Specialized in production for film and animation.

Relevant Softwares: Excel and google apps, After Effects, Cinema 4D, Autodesk Maya, Mari, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Adobe Premier, ShotGun, Foundry Nuke.

Bilingual English and Spanish

Relevant information: Photography, Graphic Design, Communication Strategy, Art Direction, on set supervisor for advertising and film production, Compositing and post production, lighting, Rendering, Color correction, 2D and 3D tracking.

Experience

SraX productions
VFX Producer/PostProduction & Studio Manager
September 2020 - Present (1 year 1 month)

Page 1 of 4

FX Animation Barcelona 3D and Film School

6 years 3 months

Production coordinator & Producer for VFX, Film, Animation and Video games

December 2019 - September 2020 (10 months)

Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain

Head Of Department for Motion Graphics and VFX Compositing May 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 8 months)

Barcelona Area, Spain

Maintain relations between departments to follow production workflows for film, animation, video games, 2D and 3D content.

Create and update material based on the industry standard.

Supervise and coordinate groups to ensure the learning and correct application of concepts, techniques and softwares; as well us following up projects providing solutions to create high quality results and finishings; as well as providing comfortable environment to teams.

On set supervising, as well as working closely with, producers, lighting team, directors, developers for advertising and film content.

Follow corporate guidelines and understand project needs.

Instructor of Motion Graphics and VFX Compositing July 2014 - 2019 (5 years)

Barcelona Area, Spain

Ensure the learning of 2D and 3D foundations and techniques, design concepts, composition and motion graphics.

Creating high quality video content.

Comfortable working in teamwork as well as leading groups.

Advanced color correction and Composition techniques.

Create custom workflows and courses.

Freelance

Creative Motion Designer and Compositor April 2013 - September 2020 (7 years 6 months)

Visual management and coordination of projects for various brands starting from research, concept, design, compositing, and finishing. As well as story

boarding, new design proposals combined with video editing, motion graphics and Art direction.

SALÓ DEL CINEMA I LES SÈRIES

Talk: How to create professional 3D/2D Motion Graphics for series, advertising and cinema

January 2017 - 2017 (less than a year)

Barcelona Area, Spain

How to bring together softwares us After Effects, Illustrator and Cinema 4D to generate more powerful contents.

Sponsore by FXANIMATION Barcelona 3D and Film School.

Odysii

Senior Creative Design

June 2011 - August 2014 (3 years 3 months)

Barcelona Area, Spain

http://www.odysiibcn.es/

Production of multimedia, print and digital content for on and off campaigns.

Design and motion graphics for digital channels in Spain and Portugal.

Create presentations, storyboards and concepts. Work in collaboration with programmers, suppliers and marketing department.

Direct contact with clients.

Understanding of briefs.

Follow corporate guidelines.

Clients: Acer Spain, Corte Inglés, Shopping malls, Sports center among others.

Hispanic Connections, Inc.

Creative Design

January 2009 - May 2010 (1 year 5 months)

United States

Hispanic Connections inc, creates a bridge between businesses & organizations to the hispanic market in the United States.

My job was to develop online and offline campaigns, creating corporate and promotional material.

Experience mastering English and Spanish in the area of design and business.

Buoka Creative Co.
Junior Graphic Designer
January 2007 - January 2008 (1 year 1 month)

Bogotá, Colombia

Developed editorial design, advertising and branding.

Clients: Magazine Thunder Road, Newspaper Todo Deportes and Paisano.

Casa Editorial El Tiempo Multimedia Graphic Designer January 2006 - November 2006 (11 months) Bogotá, Colombia

Colombia's national newspaper.

My job was the production of videos and animations for events and activities.

Clients: El Tiempo, International Book Fair.

Luma Studio. Asociados S.A.S Junior Graphic Designer March 2005 - October 2005 (8 months) Bogotá, Colombia

Multimedia and printing design.

Clients: Project PAC Chocó collided with the Dutch embassy, School of Photography and Movies Zona Cinco.

Education

University of California, Los Angeles

Entertainment Financing: From First \$ to Distribution of Profits, Entertainment Financing - UCLA Extension · (June 2021 - September 2021)

Mr. Cohl, Consultoría y gestión de proyectos de Animación Curso de ayudante de producción de Animación, 3D animation · (2020 - 2020)

Elisava, Barcelona School of Design and Engineering

Master's Degree, Art Direction and Communication Strategies · (2008 - 2009)

University Jorge Tadeo Lozano. Bogotá, Colombia Bachelor's Degree, Undergraduate Degree Graphic Design (2002 - 2005)

FX Animation Barcelona 3D and Film School

Master in Post Production, Composition and Visual Effects, Compositor and Motion Graphics \cdot (2013 - 2014)